<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>OBIMS Overview</title>
    <author>Vincent Ferretti</author>
    <author>Nancy Lambert</author>
    <author>Philippe Laflamme</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="BIMS Overview">
      <subsection name="The OBiBa Biobank Information Management System">

        <p>
          The Canadian Partnership Against Cancer (CPAC) network of biobanks was launched in 2008 and comprises
          <strong>five
            major Canadian cohorts</strong> who aim to recruit a total of 300 000 participants over the next 3 years. They are: British Columbia, <a href="http://www.cancerboard.ab.ca/tomorrow/">The Tomorrow Project</a> in Alberta, <a href="http://www.p3gobservatory.org/catalogue.htm?studyId=103">Ontario Cohort Consortium</a>, <a href="http://www.cartagene.qc.ca">CARTaGENE</a> in Quebec and finally Atlantic. 
        </p>

        <p>The OBiBa Consortium mission is to build a configurable biobank information management system, generic
          enough to meet the specific requirements of the 5 partners and, by the same token, any other biobanks that
          would
          be interested in using it.</p>

        <p>The OBiBa system currently includes two main components, each of one which corresponds to a distinct
          sub-project (see figure bellow): </p>

        <ol>
          <li>
            <strong>Onyx: The assessment center application</strong>
            <br />
            Participants are invited by the enrolment unit to show up at a designated assessment center for signing
            consent form, answering questionnaires on health and life style, submitting to physical measurements and
            giving bio-samples. The Onyx software, inspired by that of the UK biobank, consists of independent web-based
            data collection modules (basically one for each stage) integrated together in a configurable manner to track
            participant interviews and collect data. To know more, see the
            <a href="onyx.html">Onyx section</a>.
          </li>

          <li>
            <strong>DCC: The Data Coordinating Center application</strong>
            <br />
            Once collected in assessment centers, data are transferred, processed and stored into the main study
            database. The DCC application is a web-based application linked to this database which provides a metadata
            catalogue of the variables of a study as well as querying and reporting tools for administrative and
            scientific purposes. The DCC application is currently in the design phase. This work is undertaken in
            collaboration with the CPAC harmonisation task force lead by Dr. Isabel Fortier, director of the
            <a href="http://www.p3gobservatory.org">P3G Observatory</a>
            and leader of the
            <a href="http://www.p3gobservatory.org/datashaper/explorer.htm">DataSHaPER</a>
            project. There is no source code available yet. Coding should start during winter 2009.
          </li>
        </ol>

        <p>A long term goal is to add a third component that will link the five Canadian cohort databases together and
          provide researchers with a single point of entry for querying the whole CPAC data set. We envision
          implementing
          a federated databases solution given the complexity of maintaining a central data warehouse.</p>

        <p>
          <a name="bims-vision" />
          <img src="images/bims-overview.png" width="600px" />
          Figure 1: Components and actors of the OBiBa biobank information management system.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
