<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Onyx - The Assessment Center Application</title>
    <author>Vincent Ferretti</author>
    <author>Nancy Lambert</author>
    <author>Philippe Laflamme</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Introduction">
      <p>Onyx is the application that manages participant interviews at the assessment centers. This
      application is currently under development by a team of 8 people. The timelines are short.. Very little
      documentation is available for now and this web site is far from complete due to lack of time. If you are
      interested in knowing more about the project or wish to collaborate, please contact directly <a href="mailto:info@obiba.org">info@obiba.org</a>.org. Only
      a very general overview of the system is provided here.</p> 
    </section>
    <section name="Overview">
      <p>In Onyx, an interview is represented formally as a sequence of stages that participants have to pass through
        in order to complete their visit at the assessment center. For example, the informed consent signature is
        usually the first required stage of any interview. The main responsibility of Onyx is to provide the applicative
        backbone into which independent data collection software used by stages (e.g. a CAPI software for questionnaire
        administration) can be easily plugged (see figure 1). This modular and generic architecture allows a very
        customizable system. Biobanks can configure Onyx for their own specific stages and software.</p>

      <p>Once configured, Onyx controls both the order and availability of the stages (e.g. no stages are available
        prior to informed consent signature) and captures many administrative parameters such as starting and ending
        times of each stage. Onyx also manages participant appointment and reception as well as data exportation to the
        study central database.</p>

      <p><img src="images/flow.png"/>Figure 1: Onyx main functionalities in blue. Orange hexagons represent data collection software or modules used in each stage.</p>

		  <subsection name="Screeshots">
        <p>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="images/screens/onyx/participant-list.png">Appointment Management</a></li>
            <li><a href="images/screens/onyx/reception.png">Participant Reception</a></li>
            <li><a href="images/screens/onyx/participant-interview.png">Participant Interview</a></li>
            <li><a href="images/screens/onyx/popup.png">Starting an Interview Stage</a></li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="CPAC Data Collection Modules">
        <p>The OBiBa team is currently developing a series of stage modules for the CPAC cohorts. Each of them uses
          generic data models and tools that can be configured to meet requirements of other biobanks. These modules are:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <a href="marble.html">Marble - Consent</a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="quartz.html">Quartz - CAPI</a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="jade.html">Jade - Physical Measurements</a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="ruby.html">Ruby - Sample Collection</a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="mica.html">Mica - Conclusion</a>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>
